Guide to the Socialist Minute Books (New York, N.Y.) TAM.056.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Minute Books (New York, N.Y.)
1872-1907
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tageblatt
Social-Democratic Party of America
Socialist Labor Party
Shirt, Waist, and Laundry Workers International Union
Arbeiterzeitung
TAM.056.001
4 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box.
The Socialist Party (U.S.), founded in 1901, attracted numerous individuals and/or splinter groups from other socialist groupings. With these individuals/groups in the New York metropolitan area came portions of the records of several socialist organizations, notably the minute books from the Socialist Labor Party, the Social Democratic Party (and from other organizations) that comprise this collection.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version; microfilm call number is Film R-7124, Reels 1-2.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Rand School Archives, 1962. The accession number associated with this collection is 1962.004.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Socialist Party (U.S.), founded in 1901, attracted numerous individuals and/or splinter groups from other socialist groupings. With these individuals/groups in the New York metropolitan area came portions of the records of several socialist organizations, and it is these materials that comprise this collection.
Scope and Contents
The Socialist Minute Books, 1872 1907, consist of 32 volumes pertaining to the Socialist Labor Party, Social Democratic Party, and other socialist organizations. The volumes in this collection have been assigned frame numbers, 1-31; volume 14 has a supplementary volume with the frame number, 14a. The frame numbers and the title of each volume is located in the complete reel list which follows this description of the arrangement of the collection. The researcher should also note that an error was made in the targeting for this collection. On each frame, the word "Series" appears adjacent to the frame number. This term should actually be interpreted as "Collection".
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Party Minutes, 1900-1936 (Tamiment 056.006)
Minutes (administrative records); New York (N.Y.); Socialism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; International Vestmakers Union
- Arbeiterzeitung Constitution and Minutes, New York City, Nov 16, 1872-Oct 12, 1874; 131696 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  Film R-7124, Reel 1; Frame I:1
- Philadelphia Tageblatt Minutes, Nov 14, 1877-Jul 29, 1878; 131695 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:2
- Socialist Labor Party (Sozialistische Arbeiter Partei) Minutes, New York City, Oct 9, 1878-Sep 22, 1888; 131694 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:3
- Socialist Labor Party, Central Committee Minutes, New York City, Jan 2, 1880-Feb 8, 1881; 131693 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:4
- Socialist Labor Party, Recording Secretary's Book: Central Committee Minutes, Roll of Officers, Roll of Delegates, and Ledger Accounts, New York City, Jul 9, 1881-Jun 1, 1883; 131692 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:5
- Socialist Labor Party (Sozialistische Arbeiter Partei), Central Committee Minutes, New York City, Jun 12, 1883-Jun 17, 1884; 131691 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:6
- Socialist Labor Party, Vergnugungs Committee Minutes, New York City, May 7, 1886-Jan 19, 1888; 131690 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:7
- Socialist Labor Party, Central Committee Minutes, New York City, Apr 1, 1886-Mar 25, 1897; 131689 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:8
- Socialist Labor Party, Central Committee Minutes, New York City, Oct 27, 1891-Apr 26, 1892; 131688 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:9
- Socialist Labor Party, City Committee Minutes, New York City, Oct 2, 1888-Sep 19, 1889; 131687 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:10
- Socialist Labor Party, Branch 12 Minutes, New York City, Mar 9, 1888-Oct 17, 1889; 131686 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 1: Frame I:11
- Socialist Labor Party, Kings County Minutes, New York City, Mar 30, 1891-May 25, 1891; Mar 20, 1895-Jun 15, 1896; 131685 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:12
- Socialist Labor Party, Kings County Committee Minutes, New York City, Nov 29, 1895-Feb 12, 1897; 131684 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:13
- Philadelphia Tageblatt Publication Society Minutes, Dec 9, 1896-Apr 25, 1897; 131683 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:14
- Socialist Labor Party, Convention Proceedings, New York City, Dec 20, 1896-Apr 25, 1897; 131682 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Socialist Labor Party, Grievance Committee Minutes, New York City, Aug 2, 1898-Jul 20, 1900; 131681 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:15
- Socialist Labor Party, City Executive Committee Minutes; May Day Conference Minutes, New York City, Jul 13, 1899-Jul 23, 1902; Jan 15, 1898-Apr 11, 1899; 131680 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:16
- Socialist Labor Party, General Committee Minutes, New York City, Jul 23, 1899-May 14, 1904; 131679 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:17
- Social Democratic Party, May Day Parade Conference Minutes, New York City, Oct 6, 1899; Mar 16, 1900-Apr 27, 1900; 131678 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:18
- Social Democratic Party, Municipal Committee Minutes, New York City, Dec 2, 1900-Jan 13, 1901; 131677 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:19
- Socialist Labor Party, 31st Assembly District Minutes, Social Democratic Party, City Campaign Committee Minutes, New York City, Nov 2, 1898-Apr 27, 1899, [Oct] 1900-Oct 31, 1900; 131676 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:20
- Social Democratic Party, Executive Committee Minutes, New York City, Jul 27, 1902-Jan 19, 1904; 131675 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:21
- Social Democratic Party, Grievance Committee Minutes, New York City, Mar 7, 1903-Jun 4, 1903; 131674 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:22
- Social Democratic Party, Sixth and Tenth Assembly Dis­tricts' Minutes, New York City, Aug 4, 1903-Jun 21, 1906; 131673 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:23
- Social Democratic Party, City Executive Committee Minutes, New York City, Feb 2, 1904-Feb 6, 1905; 131672 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:24
- Social Democratic Party, City Executive Committee Minutes, New York City, Feb 13, 1905-Apr 30, 1906; 131671 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:25
- Social Democratic Party, City Convention Minutes, New York City, Jun 22, 1901; 131670 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:26
- Shirt Waist and Laundry Workers International Union Minutes, New York City, Sep 13, 1902-Nov 4, 1904; 131669 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:27
- Social Democratic Party, General Committee Minutes, New York City, Jun 11, 1904-Apr 14, 1906; 131668 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:28
- Social Democratic Party, Thirtieth Assembly District Minutes, New York City, May 11, 1904-Jan 23, 1907; 131666 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:30
- Social Democratic Party, New York State Committee Minutes, Aug 23, 1904-May 23, 1906; 131667 (Box 8)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:29
- Socialist Party, General Committee Minutes, New York City, Apr 28, 1906-Dec 22, 1906; 131665 (Box 8)
  Film R-7124, Reel 2: Frame I:31